RG 062:142, Town of Tolland
Connecticut State Library
Town of Tolland records
1709-1920
Connecticut State Library
Tolland (Conn.)
26 cubic feet
Administrative, court, election, church, school, tax and vital records for the town of Tolland.
RG062_142
T000502
Historical Note
The town of Tolland was named in May 1715 and incorporated in May 1722.
Scope and Content
Administrative, court, election, church, school, tax and vital records for the town of Tolland.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Connecticut. Justice of the Peace (Tolland)
Subjects:
Elections -- Connecticut -- Tolland -- Statistics; Voting -- Connecticut -- Tolland -- Statistics; Church records and registers -- Connecticut -- Tolland; Public welfare -- Connecticut -- Tolland; School enrollment -- Connecticut -- Tolland -- Statistics; Deeds -- Connecticut -- Tolland; Soldiers -- Connecticut -- Tolland; Justices of the peace -- Connecticut -- Tolland; Writs -- Connecticut -- Tolland; Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- Tolland -- Registers; Taxation -- Connecticut -- Tolland -- Registers; Local taxation -- Connecticut -- Tolland -- Registers; Property tax -- Connecticut -- Tolland -- Registers
Places:
Tolland (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence; Tolland (Conn.) -- Statistics, Vital
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1709-1920
  - Town meeting records, 1798-1920 (Box Box 1)
  - Election returns, 1788-1900 (Box Box 1)
  - Certificates of electors, undated (Box Box 1)
  - Voters' lists, 1837-1918 (Box Box 2)
  - Meeting house reports, 1754-1804 (Box Box 3)
  - Appointments of administrators, 1783-1844 (Box Box 3)
  - Lists of jurors, 1786-1852 (Box Box 3)
  - Oaths of freemen, 1802-1817 (Box Box 3)
  - Smallpox regulations, 1797-1803 (Box Box 3)
  - Statements of election expenses, 1895-1906 (Box Box 3)
  - Appointments, election and oaths of town officials, 1894-1902 (Box Box 3)
  - Bonds, 1858-1860 (Box Box 3)
  - Certificates of church membership, 1792-1810 (Box Box 3)
  - Indentures, 1758-1835 (Box Box 3)
  - Records and inventories relating to care of the poor, 1830-1890 (Box Box 3)
  - School returns, circa 1827-1873 (Box Box 4)
  - School district reports, minutes and contracts, 1810-1878 (Box Box 5)
  - Highway and bridge records, 1724-1848 (Box Box 5)
  - Tax abstracts, 1733-1788 (Box Box 6)
  - Tax receipts, lists, and memoranda, 1860-1915 (Box Box 6)
  - Abatements, 1741-1901 (Box Box 6)
  - Tax abstracts, 1810-1821 (Box Box 7)
    Tax abstracts for 1822 to 1909 are in boxes 24-34.
  - Deeds, school reports and mortgages, 1741-1909 (Box Boxes 8-9)
  - Birth, marriage and death certificates and abstract reports, 1851-1900 (Box Boxes 10-11)
  - Seating in the meeting house, deeds, court and probate records, circa 1750-1900 (Box Box 12)
  - Assorted records, including tax, school, highway and court records, circa 1752-1920 (Box Boxes 13-14)
  - Military service records, 1850-1864 (Box Box 15)
  - Town receipts, bills, orders for payment, abatements and Selectmen's reports, 1836-1910 (Box Box 16)
  - Orders, 1816-1818, 1842-1872 (Box Box 17)
  - Selectmen's accounts, 1812-1829 (Box Box 17)
  - School Society Committee orders, 1839 (Box Box 17)
  - Orders drawn, 1891-1898 (Box Box 17)
  - School district accounts, 1783-1813 (Box Box 17)
  - Town orders for payment, 1784-1791 (Box Box 17a)
  - Town orders for payment, 1796-1800 (Box Box 17b)
  - Orders, receipts and accounts, 1709-1841 (Box Box 18)
  - Promissory notes, 1786-1836 (Box Box 19)
  - Lists of electors, 1820-1848 (Box Box 19)
  - Accounts, 1796-1848 (Box Box 19)
  - Auditors' reports, 1820-1824 (Box Box 19)
  - Correspondence; Selectmen's account, 1818-1821 (Box Box 19)
  - Books of orders, 1784-1793 (Box Box 19)
  - Receipts, undated (Box Box 19)
  - Bills, 1889-1913 (Box Box 20)
  - Justice court records, 1789-1874 (Box Boxes 21-22)
  - Writs of attachment, 1789-1841 (Box Box 23)
  - Tax abstracts
    Boxes 26 and 27 are on oversize shelving.
    - 1822, 1823, 1824, 1825, 1826, 1827, 1828, 1829 (Box Box 24)
    - 1830, 1831, 1832, 1833, 1834, 1835, 1836, 1837, 1838 (Box Box 25)
    - 1839, 1840, 1841, 1842, 1843, 1844, 1845, 1846, 1848, 1849 (Box Box 26)
    - 1850, 1851, 1852, 1853, 1854, 1855, 1856, 1857, 1858, 1859 (Box Box 27)
    - 1860, 1861, 1862, 1863, 1864, 1865, 1866, 1867, 1868, 1869 (Box Box 28)
    - 1870, 1871, 1872, 1873, 1874, 1875, 1876, 1877, 1878, 1879 (Box Box 29)
    - 1880, 1881, 1882, 1883, 1884, 1885, 1886 (Box Box 30)
    - 1887, 1888, 1889, 1890, 1891, 1892 (Box Box 31)
    - 1893, 1894, 1895, 1896, 1897, 1898, 1899 (Box Box 32)
    - 1900, 1901, 1902, 1903, 1904 (Box Box 33)
    - 1905, 1906, 1907, 1908, 1909 (Box Box 34)
  - Lists of voters, 1857-1860, 1860-1864, 1865-1868; 3 volumes (Box Box 35)